This next video is on inferring
接下来的这段视频是关于推断的
I like to think of these tasks where the model takes
我喜欢把这些任务看成是模型将一个文本作为输入并进行某种分析
a text as input and perform some kind of analysis
作为输入的文本并进行某种分析
So this could be extracting labels
所以这可能是提取标签
extracting names, kind of understanding the sentiment of a text, that kind of thing
提取名字，理解文本的情感，诸如此类的事情
So if you want to extract a sentiment
因此，如果你想提取一个情感
positive or negative of a piece of text
正面或负面的文本
in the traditional machine learning workflow
在传统的机器学习工作流程中
you'd have to collect the label dataset
你必须要收集标签数据集
train a model, figure out how to deploy the model somewhere in the Cloud
训练一个模型，弄清楚如何在云端的某个地方部署这个模型
and make inferences
并做出推断
That can work pretty well
这可以很好地工作
but it was just a lot of work to go through that process
但要经历这个过程，实在是一件很费力的事情
Also, for every task such as sentiment versus extracting names versus something else
此外，对于每一项任务，如情感分析与提取名字或其他东西
you have to train and deploy a separate model
你必须训练和部署一个单独的模型
One of the really nice things about
关于大语言模型的一个好处是
large language model is that for many tasks like these
对于许多像这样的任务
you can just write a prompt and have it start generating results pretty much right away
你可以只写一个提示，然后让它马上开始生成结果
That gives tremendous speed in terms of application development
这给应用程序的开发带来了巨大的提速
You can also just use one model
你也可以只使用一个模型
one API to do many different tasks rather than needing to
一个API来完成许多不同的任务，而不需要
figure out how to train and deploy a lot of different models
弄清楚如何训练和部署许多不同的模型
With that, let's jump into the code to see how you can take advantage of this
有了这些，让我们跳进代码，看看你如何利用这个优势
Here's our usual starter code
这里是我们通常的初始代码
I'll just run that
运行这个
The most of the example I'm going to use is a review for a lamp
我使用的最多的例子，是关于一盏灯的评论
Need a nice lamp for the bedroom
卧室里需要一盏漂亮的灯
and this one additional storage, and so on
和额外存储空间的家具，等等
Let me write a prompt to classify the sentiment of this
让我写一个提示，对这个的情绪进行分类
If I want the system to tell me what is the sentiment
如果我想让系统告诉我这是什么情绪
I can just write what is the sentiment of the following product review
我可以直接写出 "以下产品评论的情感是什么"
with the usual delimiter and the review text and so on, and let's run that
加上通常的分隔符和评论文本等等，然后让我们运行这个提示
This says the sentiment of the product review is positive
这表示该产品评论的情绪是积极的
which actually seems pretty right
这实际上似乎很正确
This lamp isn't perfect, but this customer seems pretty happy
这盏灯并不完美，但这位顾客看起来很满意
Seems to be a great company that cares about the customers and products
这似乎是一个关心客户和产品的伟大公司
I think positive sentiment seems to be the right answer
我认为积极的情绪似乎是正确的答案
Now, this prints out the entire sentence
现在，这就把整个句子打印出来
the sentiment of the product review is positive
该产品评论的情绪是积极的
If you wanted to give a more concise response to make it easier for post-processing
如果你想给出一个更简洁的回答，以便于后期处理
I can take this prompt and add another instruction
我可以在这个提示中加入另一条指令
to give you answers to single word
只给你一个单词的答案
either positive or negative
正面或负面
It just prints out positive like this, which makes it easier for a piece of text
它只是像这样打印出正面，这对一段文字来说更容易
to take this output and process it and do something with it
来处理这个输出，并对它做一些处理
Let's look at another prompt
让我们看一下另一个提示
Again, still using the lamp review
再来一遍，仍然使用关于台灯的评论
Here, I have it identify a list of
在这里，我让它识别一个列表
emotions that the writer of the following review is expressing
以下评论的作者所表达的情绪
including no more than five items in this list
在这个列表中包括不超过五个项目
Large language models are pretty good at
大语言模型在以下方面相当出色
extracting specific things out of a piece of text
从一段文本中提取特定的东西
In this case, we're expressing the emotions
在这种情况下，我们要表达的是情绪
This could be useful for understanding how
这对于了解
your customers think about a particular product
你的客户对某一特定产品的看法
For a lot of customer support organizations
对于很多客户支持机构来说，了解客户对产品的看法很重要
it's important to understand if a particular user is extremely upset
理解一个特定的用户是否对你的产品非常不满是非常重要的
You might have a different classification problem like this
你可能有这样一个不同的分类问题
is the writer of the following review expressing anger?
下面这篇评论的作者是否在表达愤怒？
Because if someone is really angry
因为如果某人真的很生气
it might merit paying extra attention to have a customer review
它可能值得付出额外的关注来获得客户评论
to have customer support or customer success
获得客户支持或成功拿下客户
reach out to figure what's going on and make things right for the customer
伸出援手，弄清楚发生了什么事，并为客户把事情做好
In this case, the customer is not angry
在这种情况下，客户并不生气
Notice that with supervised learning
注意，有了监督学习
if I had wanted to build all of these classifiers
如果我想建立所有这些分类器
there's no way I would have been able to do this with
我不可能用监督学习在短短几分钟内完成这些工作
supervised learning in just a few minutes that you saw me do so in this video
而你在这段视频中看到我这样做了
I'd encourage you to pause this video and try changing some of these prompts
我鼓励你暂停这个视频，并尝试改变其中的一些提示
Maybe ask if the customer is expressing delight or ask if there are
也许问一下客户是否表达了喜悦之情，或者问一下是否有
any missing parts and see if you can get a prompt to
任何缺失的部分，看看你是否能得到一个提示来
make different inferences about this lab review
对这个实验室进行不同的推断
Let me show some more things that you can do with this system
让我再展示一下你可以用这个系统做的一些事情
specifically extracting richer information from a customer review
特别是从客户评论中提取更丰富的信息
Information extraction is the part of NLP
信息提取是NLP的一部分
of natural language processing that relates to taking a piece of
自然语言处理的一部分，它涉及到将一段文本
text and extracting certain things that you want to know from the text
并从文本中提取出你想知道的某些东西
In this prompt, I'm asking it
在这个提示中，我问它
identify the following items
确定以下项目
the item purchase and the name of the company that made the item
购买的物品和制造该物品的公司名称
Again, if you are trying to summarize many reviews from an online shopping e-commerce website
同样，如果你想从一个在线购物的电子商务网站上总结出许多评论
it might be useful for your large collection of
对于你收集的大量评论来说
reviews to figure out what were the items
弄清楚这些评论所涉及的物品可能会很有用
who made the item, figure out positive and negative sentiment
可以通过分析评论中的内容，找出评论涉及的物品制造商
to track trends about positive or negative sentiment for
并确定积极和消极情绪
specific items or for specific manufacturers
以追踪特定物品或制造商的积极或消极情绪趋势
In this example, I'm going to ask it to format your response as
在这个例子中，我将要求它把响应格式化为
a JSON object with item and brand as the keys
一个以项目和品牌为键的JSON对象
If I do that, it says the item is a lamp
如果我这样做了，它就会说这个物品是一盏灯
the brand is Luminar
品牌是Luminar
and you can easily load this into
你可以很容易地将其加载到
Python dictionary to then do additional processing on this output
Python字典中，然后对这个输出做额外的处理
In the examples we've gone through
在我们所经历的例子中
you saw how to write a prompt to recognize the sentiment
你看到了如何写一个提示来识别情感
figure out if someone is angry
弄清某人是否生气
and then also extract the item and the brand
然后再提取物品和品牌
One way to extract all of this information would be to use three or four prompts
提取所有这些信息的一个方法是使用三或四个提示语
and call get_completion three times or four times
并调用三次或四次get_completion
extract these different fields one at a time
一次一次地提取这些不同的字段
But it turns out you can actually write a single prompt
但事实证明，你实际上可以只写一个提示符
to extract all of this information at the same time
来同时提取所有这些信息
Let's say identify the following items
比方说识别以下项目
extract sentiment, is a reviewer expressing anger
提取情绪，是评论者表达愤怒
item purchase, company animated
项目的购买，公司的动画
Then here, I'm also going to tell it to format the anger value as a Boolean value
然后在这里，我还要告诉它把愤怒值格式化为一个布尔值
Let me run that
让我运行它
This outputs a JSON where sentiment is positive
这将输出一个JSON，其中情绪是积极的
anger, and then no quotes around false
愤怒，然后在false周围没有引号
because it also just output it as a Boolean value
因为它也只是把它输出为一个布尔值
Extracted the item as lamp with additional storage instead of lamp
提取出"lamp with additional storage"作为物品，而不仅仅是"lamp"
Seems okay
看起来还不错
But this way, you can extract multiple fields out of
这种方法让你只需一个提示
a piece of text with just a single prompt
就可以从一段文本中提取多个字段
As usual, please feel free to pause the video
像往常一样，请随意暂停视频
and play with different variations on this yourself
并在此基础上试玩一下，感受不同变化
Or maybe even try typing in a totally different review to see if you
或者甚至可以尝试输入一个完全不同的评论，看看你是否
can still extract these things accurately
能否仍然准确地提取这些东西
Now, one of the cool applications I've seen of
现在，我看到大型语言模型很酷的应用之一
large language models is inferring topics
是推断主题
Given a long piece of text
给出一段长的文字
what is this piece of text about?
这段文字是关于什么的？
What are the topics?
主题是什么？
Here's a fictitious newspaper article about how
这是一篇虚构的报纸文章，关于如何
government workers feel about the agency they work for
政府工作人员对他们所工作的机构的感受
The recent survey conducted by government and so on
最近由政府等进行的调查
results reviewed at NASA was
结果审查，NASA是
a popular department with high satisfaction rating
一个受欢迎的部门，满意度很高
I am a fan of NASA
我是NASA的粉丝
love the work they do, but this is a fictitious article
喜欢他们所做的工作，但这是一篇虚构的文章
Given an article like this
鉴于这样的文章
we can ask it with this prompt
我们可以用这个提示来问它
determine five topics that are being discussed in the following text
确定以下文本中讨论的五个主题
Let's make each item one or two words long
让我们把每一项都写成一到两个字的长度
for my response, comma separated list
为我的回答，用逗号分隔的列表
If we run that
如果我们运行这个
we get out this article is about a government survey
我们就会发现，这篇文章是关于政府调查的
is about job satisfaction, is about NASA, and so on
是关于工作满意度的，是关于NASA的，等等
Overall, I think pretty nice extraction of a list of topics
总的来说，我认为相当不错的主题列表的提取
Of course, you can also split it so you get
当然，你也可以把它分开，这样你就可以得到
a Python list with the five topics that this article was about
一个包含这篇文章所涉及的五个主题的Python列表
If you have a collection of articles and extract topics
如果你有一个文章的集合，并提取主题
you can then also use
那么你还可以使用
a large language model to help you index into different topics
一个大语言模型来帮助你索引到不同的主题
Let me use a slightly different topic list
让我用一个稍微不同的主题列表
Let's say that we're a news websites or something
比方说，我们是一个新闻网站或其他什么
and these are the topics we track
而这些是我们追踪的主题
NASA, local government, engineering
NASA，当地政府，工程
employee satisfaction, federal government
员工满意度，联邦政府
Let's say you want to figure out
比方说，你想弄清楚
given a news article
给出一篇新闻文章
which of these topics are covered in that news article
这篇新闻报道中涉及哪些主题
Here's a prompt that I can use
这里有一个提示，我可以使用
I'm going to say, determine whether each item in
我想说的是，确定 "有趣的主题清单 "中的每一项
the fun list of topics is a topic in the text below
是否是下面文本中的一个主题
Give your answers and this is 01 for each topic
给出你的答案，这是每个话题的01
Great. This is the same story text as before
很好。这是和之前一样的故事文本
This thing is a story. It is about NASA
这个东西是一个故事。它是关于NASA的
It's not about local governments, not about engineering
这不是关于地方政府，不是关于工程
It is about employee satisfaction and it is about federal government
它是关于员工满意度的，它是关于联邦政府的
With this, in machine learning
有了这个，在机器学习中
this is sometimes called a zero-shot learning algorithm
这有时被称为 "零示例学习算法"
because we didn't give it any training data that was labeled
因为我们没有给它任何有标签的训练数据
That's zero-shot
这就是零示例
With just a prompt
只需一个提示
it was able to determine which of
它就能够确定哪些
these topics are covered in that news article
这些主题在那篇新闻报道中被涵盖
If you want to generate a news alert
如果你想生成一个新闻警报
so that process news and I really like a lot of work that NASA does
这样处理新闻，我真的很喜欢NASA做的很多工作
If you want to build a system that can take this
如果你想建立一个系统，可以把这个
put this information into a dictionary and whenever
把这些信息放到一个字典里，每当
NASA news pops up, print alert
NASA的新闻出现，就打印提醒
new NASA story, they can use this to very quickly take any article
新的NASA故事，他们可以用这个来非常迅速地采取任何文章
figure out what topics it is about
弄清楚它是关于什么主题的
and if the topic includes NASA
如果该主题包括NASA
have it print out alert, new NASA story
让它打印出警报，新的NASA故事
Just one thing, I use this topic dictionary down here
只有一件事，我在下面使用这个主题词典
This prompt that I use up here isn't very robust
我在上面使用的这个提示不是很强大
If I wanted a production system
如果我想要一个生产系统
I would probably have it output the answer in JSON format
我可能会让它以JSON格式输出答案
rather than as a list because the output
而不是作为一个列表，因为输出的
of the large language model can be a little bit inconsistent
大语言模型会有一点不一致
This is actually a pretty brittle piece of code
这实际上是一段很脆弱 的代码
But if you want, when you're done watching this video
但是，如果你想，当你看完这个视频后
feel free to see if you can figure out how to modify this prompt
可以看看你能不能想出办法来修改这个提示
to have it output JSON instead of a list like this
让它输出JSON而不是像这样的一个列表
and then have a more robust way to tell if a particular article is a story about NASA
然后有一个更强大的方法来判断某篇文章是否是关于NASA的故事
So that's it for inferring
所以，这就是推断的内容
In just a few minutes
在短短的几分钟内
you can build multiple systems for making inferences about
你可以建立多个系统，对文本进行推断
text that previously just would have taken days or
这些推断以前需要一名熟练的机器学习开发人员
even weeks for a skilled machine learning developer
花费数天甚至数周才能完成
I find this very exciting that both for
我认为，无论是对于熟练的机器学习开发人员
skilled machine learning developers as well as for
还是机器学习新手而言
people that are newer to machine learning
这都是非常令人兴奋的消息
you can now use prompting to very quickly build and start
你现在可以使用提示来非常快速地建立并开始
making inferences on pretty complicated natural language processing tasks like these
对这些相当复杂的自然语言处理任务做出推断
In the next video
在下一个视频中
we'll continue to talk about exciting things you could do with
我们将继续讨论令人激动的事情，你可以用
large language models and we'll go on to transforming
大语言模型，我们将继续进行转换
How can you take one piece of text and transform it into
把一段文本转换为
a different piece of text such as translated to a different language
不同的文本，如翻译成不同的语言
Let's go on to the next video
让我们继续看下一个视频